* Log in

Privacy Policy
==============

Last Updated : March, 2024

* Agreements

---------------------------------------------------------------------

We at Shoutcast SPRL (“Shoutcast”, “we”, “us” or “our”) respect your privacy and recognize the importance of providing a secure environment for your personal data. Therefore, we are committed to being transparent about how we collect and process your personal data. The purpose of this privacy notice (“Privacy Notice”) is to inform you as a user about why and how we process your personal data (that is any information that can be linked or attributed to you, “Personal Data”) when use our website including our platform (“Website”) which helps you to stream or broadcast your radio stations and monetize your audience. This includes information regarding with whom we will share your Personal Data, how long we will retain it, and which rights you have in relation to the processing. This Privacy Notice applies whenever you use our Website. While using our platform, you can sign-up from <[www.shoutcast.com](http://www.shoutcast.com/)\> or we can create an account on behalf of you. Please note that the explanations provided in this Privacy Notice relate exclusively to the processing of personal data regarding the Website. When you visit Third Party Platforms they may be collecting your personal data for their own purposes. If you would like to learn more about the privacy practices of the respective partner websites through which our services and technology are provided, please review the Third Party Platform website’s privacy statement.

-------------------------------------------

In this part of our Privacy Notice, you will find general information about how we process your Personal Data when you use our Services. For specific information with more details about our processing activities, please see the service specific information below.

1. Who is responsible for the processing of your Personal Data?  
    We, Shoutcast SPRL., based at Avenue Hermann Debroux 54, 1160 Brussel, Belgium, are responsible (“the data controller”) for the processing of your Personal Data when you use our Website.
2. What types of Personal Data do we process and how do we collect it?  
    When you use our Website, as further explained, we collect, use, store, and transfer different kinds of Personal Data. As a general principle, we do not collect and do not ask you to provide any "special categories of Personal Data," which is any particularly protected information such as data concerning health, religion, political opinions or philosophical beliefs, sexual preferences, or orientation. The information we collect depends on which of our services you use and how you use them. We process the following types of your Personal Data:
    1. Personal Data provided by you  
        When you use our Website, you provide or are asked to give us certain information, including:
        * Information provided in relation to our customer service: When you contact support, we collect information about your request (subject and content of your request and any attachment you added) and your contact details (your name and email address).
        * Your account information: If you create an account to access our platform, we collect your log-in data (your email address, name, and password).
        * Your company information: If you would like to become a Shoutcast API Partner, you can apply by filling in the Shoutcast Partner form. When you fill in the form, we collect your full name, email address, company name, your country, total listening hours per month if you own any radio stations, and content of your message.
        * Your profile information: When you sign up for our platform, you can change the details you provided during account creation, and you can add your Paypal account information. Additionally, you can also change the date and number formatting and your preferred currency.
    2. Personal Data we receive from your use of our Services  
        When you use our Services, we also process device-related information and information about how you interact with our Services, including:
        * Technical information: We collect information about your device/device settings you use for the purposes described below. The information we obtain from your devices includes the type of your device, online identifiers (your IP address), geolocation data (based on your IP address), browser settings, screen resolution, and other technical information.
        * Cookie data: A "cookie" is a file of information placed on your device when you visit a website. We use cookies and similar technology such as pixels or local storage and allow third parties to use cookies and similar technology for the purposes described below. The exact process of placing cookies, and the scope of the data that may subsequently be processed is set out in our Cookie Notice.
        * Your usage: We collect information about how you use our services. This information includes the actions you take within the Website such as your number of stations, your midroll campaigns (whether you activated any midroll campaigns or not), and the status of your subscription (active or inactive).
    3. Personal Data we collect from third parties  
        In certain scenarios, we will also obtain your Personal Data from third parties, in strict compliance with applicable data protection laws and regulations. Your Personal Data are provided by the following third parties, including:
        * Your Consent String: When you visit our Website, our consent management platform (CMP) provider obtains your consent for our processing activities as well. The CMP provides us with your consent string which shall indicate your preferences on our respective processing activities.
        * Your payment details: We provide the services on our Website based on an annual subscription fee, and we use a third-party payment provider to charge payments. Our third-party payment provider partner collects your email address, credit card information, billing information, and your phone number (optional). In return, we receive the receipt of your payment including your full name, email address, date and time of the subscription, and the last 4 digits of your credit card.
3. Do we collect data from minors?  
    Our services are not targeted towards, nor intended for use by anyone under the age of 18. Therefore, we do not intentionally collect and/or categorize personal information from children. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal data from a user under 18 years of age within the scope of the Services explained in this Privacy Notice, we will delete that data as quickly as possible. If you believe that a user might be under the age of 18, please contact us.
4. For what purpose do we process your data?  
    When we act as a data controller, depending on which Services you are using and which privacy settings you have selected, we process your Personal Data for the following purposes:
    
    1. Provision and improvement of our Services
        * To provide our services
        * To allow you to use our Website
        * To create and manage your account
        * To restore your account if you ever lose access
        * To communicate with you in the context of account activation, password management
        * To simplify the registration process
        * To provide technical support and respond to your requests
        * To aggregate financial reports
        * To identify and correct any bugs/errors
    2. Providing a more user-friendly Platform Experience
        * To remember you next time you visit our Website
    3. Prevention of fraud and illegal activity
        * To enforce our policies and Terms and Conditions
        * To investigate fraud and illegal behavior
    4. Analytics and Reporting
        * To provide you reporting about the number of visits and listening to your radio station
        * To provide you reporting on the monetization of your radio stream and broadcast
        * To understand usage of our Services across all our group companies to support strategy and growth
    5. Communication
        * To provide you with customer support based on your questions, requests, or complaints
        * To send you service emails
        * To send you newsletters if you are subscribed to
    6. Compliance with our legal or regulatory obligations
        * To comply with the applicable laws (such as obtaining your consent, if you are in a consent jurisdiction -EEA or US-), including laws outside an end user’s country of residence
        * To comply with subpoenas, warrants, or other legal process
        * To respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside an end user’s country of residence
        * To enforce our terms and conditions
        * To protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates
        * To protect our rights, privacy, safety, or property, and/or that of our affiliates, end users, or others
        * To allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain

    Please see the section with service-specific information below for a more detailed description of the purposes for which we process your Personal Data.
5. On which legal basis do we process your Personal Data?  
    When we act as a data controller, we process your Personal Data for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice, based on the following legal grounds:
    
    * Your consent: We process your Personal Data if you have provided your consent via a consent management platform available on our Website for a specific purpose. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time, for example by changing your privacy settings. Please note that this will not affect any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent.
    * Performance of a contract: We process your Personal Data for the performance of a contract or to take steps prior to entering into a contract to which you are party, for example, in the context of customer service and creation of your account.
    * Compliance with legal obligations to which we are subject: We process your Personal Data to comply with legal obligations; for example, for tax and accounting purposes or legal disputes.
    * Legitimate interests: We also process your Personal Data to the extent that the processing is necessary for our legitimate interests or those of third parties while applying appropriate safeguards that protect your privacy. For example, we process your Personal Data via cookies to record your preferences related to cookies on our Website based on our legitimate interest related to be able to respect your rights or to provide you with a better user experience or we transfer your personal data across all our group companies for administrative transfers as well as to determine the size of the user base of our Services.

    Please see for additional information the section with service-specific information below.
6. With whom do we share your Personal Data?  
    We will not disclose your Personal Data to any party who is not authorized to process them. To manage our services, we will share your Personal Data internally with members of our responsible departments and technical support, and in each case only if access to your Personal Data is necessary for the performance of their roles. Moreover, and only when necessary to fulfill the purposes mentioned above, we disclose your Personal Data to the following recipients or categories of recipients or allow the following third parties to collect your Personal Data in connection with your use of our Services. This Policy does not apply to those parties, and Shoutcast is not responsible for their collection or use of information.
    
    * Vendors and service providers: We use a variety of vendors and service providers as part of, and for the purposes of, providing our Website. These could include cloud storage and cloud computing services. These vendors and service providers are subject to security and confidentiality restrictions to ensure their processing of the data is consistent with this policy.
    * External service providers: We share your Personal Data with external service providers who perform services on our behalf, like IT services, hosting and content delivery services, analytics services, and video hosting services. Where we share your Personal Data with external service providers, we have appropriate agreements in place to ensure that your Personal Data is processed in compliance with applicable data protection laws.
    * Cloud Identity provider: We use a third-party identity provider to ensure secure access to our Platform when you are signing-up and logging in. During your registration, personal data provided by you is shared with the cloud identity provider in an encrypted way and each attempt of log-ins are stored by the cloud identity provider as log files. Information in log files includes your IP address, date and time of the attempt, and information about your activity.
    * Payment service provider: We partner with a third-party payment service provider to be able to charge payments per subscription to our Platform and services. Our third-party payment service provider collects your email address, full name, billing address, your phone number (optional), and your credit card information for the transaction. Afterwards, we receive the receipts of payments to be able to confirm that subscription is completed. Please note that we do not receive or store your credit card information.
    * Lead generation partner: We use a third-party lead generation solution to create our own form, which you need to fill-in to be able to work with us as a partner. Based on the information you provided within the form, we are able to contact you for partnership with personalized offers and messaging. Information you provide is automatically stored at the database made available to us within the lead generation partner’s platform and we can send you automatically generated follow-up emails. If you choose to subscribe to our newsletter, we can send you newsletters to keep you updated about recent developments on our Platform.
    * Fraud detection service: In order to protect our forms from bots and spam, we use a third-party fraud detection service.
    * Customer support service: We use a third-party customer support service to be able to respond to your queries in an orderly manner and on a timely basis. We also created a support page to provide you a page where you can find responses to the FAQs (shoutcast.zendesk.com). When you visit our FAQs page, you are directed to the platform of the third-party customer support service provider.
    * Law enforcement, government authorities, or courts: We disclose your Personal Data in response to lawful requests to public authorities, including law enforcement, government authorities, or courts.
    * Affiliates and group companies: We share information with our affiliated companies, i.e., companies within our corporate family, which are also subject to this policy. We also share your personal data with our group companies. Where we share your personal data with our group companies, we have appropriate agreements (an intra-company data sharing agreement) in place to ensure that your personal data is processed in compliance.
    * Other third parties: We also disclose your Personal Data in the event of any contemplated or actual reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer, or other disposition of all or any portion of our business or assets (including in any insolvency or similar proceedings).

    Please see the section with service-specific information below for more information about the third parties we may share your data with. Furthermore, you can find the third parties your Personal Data may be shared below.
7. Where will my Personal Data be processed?  
    In general, if you are accessing our Services from the European Union (EU) / the European Economic Area (EEA), your data is stored on servers within the EU / EEA. However, with regard to certain activities described in this Privacy Notice, your data may also be shared outside the EU / EEA. We have implemented appropriate safeguards to protect your Personal Data when it is transferred outside the EU/EEA, including the execution of the European Commission's standard data protection clauses (also known as Model Clauses) to provide safeguards for your Personal Data.  
    For further information on, or to receive a copy of, the adequate safeguards adopted by us for the international transfer of your Personal Data, please contact us by email at [dpo@azerion.com](mailto:dpo@azerion.com). We will process any request in line with any local laws and our policies and procedures.
8. How do we protect your Personal Data?  
    We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures designed to protect your Personal Data against accidental, unlawful, or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure, or use. We update and test our security standards on an ongoing basis. In addition, we take reasonable steps to assure that third parties to whom we transfer your Personal Data provide sufficient protection of Personal Data.
9. How long do we store your Personal Data?  
    We will not retain your Personal Data longer than necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the data was collected or to fulfill our legal obligations or necessary for the establishment, exercise of defense of legal claims, or resolving disputes. In addition to this, we determine our retention periods based on our accountability obligations (to be able to demonstrate that we complied with our obligations, e.g., preserving records when you exercised one of your data subject rights), statutory requirements in countries that we are legally present including statute of limitations, the need of Personal Data for any reference to our future actions (e.g., to be able to justify an action we took or to be able to handle payments to our partners or clients) and the need of Personal Data for business processes including but not limited to development of our product. Afterwards, we will delete or anonymize your Personal Data. Additional information on how long your Personal Data is stored by our service partners can be found in the respective third-party list available below.
10. What are your rights in respect of your Personal Data?  
    To the extent permitted by applicable data protection laws and regulations, you have the following rights in relation to your Personal Data:
    
    * Access the Personal Data we hold about you, including information such as, for example, the source and categories of data, the processing purposes, the recipients (or categories thereof), and the respective retention period.
    * Request an update or correction of your Personal Data so that it is always accurate.
    * Receive your Personal Data in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format, including the right to transfer your Personal Data to another data controller.
    * Request the deletion of your Personal Data if you believe that retention is no longer necessary for the purposes indicated above.
    * Restrict the processing of your Personal Data, for example, if you have contested the accuracy of your Personal Data, and for a period of time that is sufficient to allow us to verify its accuracy.
    * Withdraw your consent at any time if your Personal Data is processed with your consent. Please note that this will not affect the lawfulness of data processing based on consent granted prior to its withdrawal.
    * Object to the processing on specific grounds relating to your particular situation, in the event and to the extent that we process your Personal Data based on our legitimate interests. In such cases, we will no longer process your Personal Data unless we have compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights, and freedoms, or for the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims. You also have the right to object where we are processing your Personal Data for profiling. In that case, we will stop processing your Personal Data for such purposes.

    You can exercise these rights by sending a request to the contact details set out below, providing your name, your email address, as well as a description of your request.  
    If you believe we have not complied with our obligations under applicable data protection laws and regulations, you can lodge a complaint with a competent data protection authority, for example, the Autorité de protection des données Gegevensbeschermingsautoriteit (APD) in Belgium.
11. How can you contact us?  
    If you have any queries about this Privacy Notice or how we use your Personal Data, please contact our customer support via our Website or our Data Protection Officer via e-mail to [dpo@azerion.com](mailto:dpo@azerion.com).
12. How often do we update this Privacy Notice?  
    We regularly review and update this Privacy Notice. When there is an important change that will have a relevant impact on the processing of your Personal Data, we will inform you by email if we have your email address. If we do not have your email address, for example because you did not create an account, we will inform you with a banner on our Website.  
    This Privacy Notice was last updated on 25 March 2024.
13. Additional Information for California Residents  
    This section for California residents supplements the information provided in this Privacy Notice and applies solely to players and others who reside in the State of California. We provide this section to comply with the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (CCPA) and the regulations issued under it; accordingly, this section addresses the specific requirements of the CCPA and should be read together with this Privacy Notice.  
    We do not sell your Personal Data. However, we may share or provide access to each of the categories of Personal Data we collect as necessary for our business purposes. We collect information that identifies, relates to, describes, references, is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular consumer or device. In particular, we have collected the following categories of personal information (envisaged by the CCPA) from consumers within the last twelve (12) months:
    
    * Category A – Identifiers (such as your device identifier, demographic information -such as your country, your username, email address, any information you may choose to provide -such as your age or your language-)
    * Category B- Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e))
    * Category D – Commercial information (such as purchase history)
    * Category F – Internet or other similar network activity (such as your interaction with our ads, your IP address)
    * Category G – Geolocation data

    The CCPA provides consumers (California residents) with specific rights regarding their personal information.  
    You have the right to access specific information, i.e., you may request that we disclose certain information to you about our collection and use of your personal information over the past 12 months.  
    You have the right to know. Under the CCPA, you have the right to request that we disclose to you what Personal Data we process about you.  
    You have the right to deletion which means that you may request that we delete any of your personal information we collected from you and retained, subject to certain exceptions. Under the CCPA, you have the right to opt out of any sale of your personal data. Please note that your right to opt out does not apply to our sharing of personal data with service providers, who are parties we engage to perform a function on our behalf and are contractually obligated to use the personal data only for that function.  
    Finally, you have a right to not be discriminated against for exercising your rights under the CCPA.  
    You can exercise these rights by sending a request to the contact details set out above, providing your name, your email address, as well as a description of your request.
14. Additional Information for Brazil Residents  
    Under the Brazilian General Data Protection Law (the “LGPD”), you have the right to access, rectify, port, erase, and confirm that we process your data. If you have given consent about processing your data, you have the right to withdraw consent anytime.

-------------------------------------------------------------

In this part of our Privacy Notice, you will find specific information on how your Personal Data is processed. For general information about data processes that apply, please see above.

### [Hosting](#hosting)

Shoutcast is hosted by external companies to provide its services to its clients. For example, every time you click on a link on our Website, the information allowing this request (e.g., device information and information on requested content) as well as online identifiers (your IP address) will be sent to the external servers. This data is used to show you the content you requested in a faster way. We process this data on the basis of our legitimate interest, to provide and improve our service and ensure its functionality.

### [Customer Service](#customer-service)

If you contact us for customer support by using our email address, we will process your email address, and the content and attachment of your request in order to provide you with support. The request history helps us to solve a newer request and is stored to defend against possible future legal claims. We process this data on the basis of performance of contract to provide you with customer support, and store this data on the basis of our legitimate interest, to improve our services, and to be able to defend possible future legal claims.

### [Creation and Administration of Your Account](#creation-and-administration-of-your-account)

In order to use our Platform, you need to have an account. We store your account data (log-in credentials and other information you provide based on whether you are an affiliate or a merchant as listed above) to allow you to log in on different devices, based on the performance of a contract. Your account data will be stored for as long as your account exists. You can delete your account at any time by submitting a deletion request to our support team or by contacting our Data Protection Officer.

### [Partner Application](#partner-application)

You can apply to become one of the partners of Shoutcast by completing the form available on our Website. Once you have completed the form, we will review the information you provided and reach out with a personalized message. We will store the information on the form as long as your account exists, if you become one of our partners. We ask for your personal data via our partner form on the basis of performance of the contract.

### [Reporting](#reporting)

In order for you to measure the effectiveness of your radio station and to analyze the amount earned from your broadcasts and streams, our Platform offers reporting. Reporting does not provide any personal data to you as it is based on aggregated data. Via reporting, you are able to see the number of your audience per hour (also per day, per week and per month), total listening hours, number of sessions per country, bandwidth usage and estimated revenue. We offer reporting based on performance of a contract.

### [Analytics](#analytics)

We use analytics services to understand the use of our Platform and improve it. For this purpose, our platform has an account manager section dedicated to analytics offering insight to the popularity of Shoutcast and radio stations. We are also able to determine the general popularity of radio streams and broadcasts based on statistics including total sessions, average unique listeners, average session duration and total sessions for longer than 30 minutes. We also process your IP address and user id to determine the number of unique users of our Services within our group companies. We process your personal data in connection with this activity and for Shoutcast analytics based on legitimate interest.

### [reCAPTCHA](#recaptcha)

We use reCAPTCHA by Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheater Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA) to secure forms and to prevent spam. reCAPTCHA is a free service that protects websites against spam and abuse. It uses advanced risk analysis techniques to keep people and bots apart. With the new API, a significant number of your valid human users will pass the reCAPTCHA challenge without having to solve a CAPTCHA. We process this data on the basis of our legitimate interest to protect our Website from bots and spam. By using reCAPTCHA, data will be transmitted to Google using Google to determine whether the visitor is human or spam. To see what data Google collects and what this data is used for, visit [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-AT](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-AT). Further documentation can be found [https://developers.google.com/recaptcha/](https://developers.google.com/recaptcha/), [https://www.google.com/recaptcha/admin/create](https://www.google.com/recaptcha/admin/create).

### [Payments](#payments)

We process your billing and invoicing information in order to make you payments of your revenue share from our monetisation services. We process this data on the basis of performance of contract to provide you our Services.

### [Third Parties of Shoutcast](#third-parties-of-shoutcast)

This list includes information about the third parties that your data may be shared with, in the way described in our Privacy Notice.

Under “Category”, you will find information about the activity your Personal Data is processed for, such as for customer service. The “Third party” indicates what third party specifically processes your data for the respective category. “Retention time” provides information about the amount of time your data is kept for. The information that is included in this column is based on the information we have received from third parties. For the most up to date information about the retention times, we refer to the privacy notice of the respective third party, which we have included in this list. In the third-party privacy notices, you will furthermore find information on how they collect and process your personal data.

| Category | Third party | Retention time | Privacy Notice |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Hosting | Amazon Web Services (AWS) | Please see their privacy notice | [AWS Privacy Notice](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/) |
| Content delivery network | Cloudflare | Please see their privacy notice | [Cloudflare Privacy Policy](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/) |
| Customer service | Zendesk, Inc. | Please see their privacy notice | [Zendesk Privacy Policy](https://www.zendesk.co.uk/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/) |
| Cloud identity provider | Auth0 | Please see their privacy notice | [Auth0 Privacy Notice](https://www.okta.com/privacy-policy/) |
| Payment Service Provider | Stripe | Please see their privacy notice | [Stripe Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/privacy) |
| Lead Generation Partner | HubSpot | Please see their privacy notice | [HubSpot Privacy Policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy) |
| Fraud Detection Service | Google reCAPTCHA | Please see their privacy notice | [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-US) |

### Plans

### More

### Support

[](https://www.shoutcast.com/)© 2024Proud member of[](https://targetspot.com/)

© 2024
